Cameron Bentley

cibentle@edu.uwaterloo.ca | 587-703-6830

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

BASC IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING Expected 2021 | Waterloo, ON

SKILLS

CAD/TECHNICAL DRAFTING

CAD & Markup Software
SolidWorks • AutoCAD • Fusion 360 •
BlueBeam Revu

Competencies GD&T • P&IDs • DFM

PROGRAMMING

Experienced

C++ • VBA • Bash • HTML

Fundamental Knowledge Python • JavaScript • CSS • Git Versioning

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION

Operating Systems
Linux • Windows Server

Software

MySQL • Docker • Hyper-V • apache • nginx • WordPress

Office Software

Word • Excel (VBA, Power Pivot, Power Query) • PowerPoint • LaTeX • Photoshop

COURSEWORK

Electrical Circuits & Instrumentation Electromechanical Devices & Power Processing

Structure & Properties of Materials Control of Properties of Materials Mechanics of Deformable Solids

ADDITIONAL INFO

Certifications & Endorsements
Driver's Licence • H₂S Alive • WHMIS

Citizenship

Canadian & EU Citizenship (UK)

Interests

Automotive • Aerospace • Computers • Robotics

Links

LinkedIn: cameron-bentley

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I am a highly motivated Mechanical Engineering student with strong administration and design skills and a strong interest in the automotive industry. I am ambitious to develop new skills through challenging work placements, as well as to experience new industries and locations. I am capable of working in fast-paced environments as both a leader and a member.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AECON GROUP INC. | Engineering Intern - Calgary Office January 2018 - April 2018 | Calgary, AB

- Office intern during pre-build phase of CNRL's Kirby North metering station.
- Created Site-Specific Safety Plan, Emergency Response Procedure and other critical safety & regulatory documentation.
- Developed procurement contracts and cost comparisons between vendors.
- Processed procurement information with SAP and managed document control.
- Collaborated in development of construction schedule using Primavera P6.
- Reviewed drawings, models, and PFDs to ensure accuracy prior to issuance.
- Automated reporting, document control, and other office processes with Power Pivot, VBA, and Bluebeam.

AECON GROUP INC. | Engineering Intern - On-Site

May 2017 - August 2017 | Fort St. John, BC

- On-site intern during a gas cogeneration facility turnaround operation.
- Assisted with project controls, planning, scheduling, QC, and reporting.
- Developed red line corrections and P&ID's for in-field revisions to IFC drawings.
- Analysed productivity and other metrics and created reports on inefficiencies to maximize productivity and minimize costs.
- Automated reporting and other office processes with Power Pivot and VBA.

PROJECTS

WATSAT SATELLITE DESIGN TEAM | STRUCTURES SUBSYSTEM LEAD September 2016 - Present | Waterloo, ON

- Designed components for CubeSat satellite structural redesign.
- Collaborated with other subsystems to integrate attitude control hardware and communications antennas into the satellite frame.
- Documented and simulated structural design properties for presentation at the Canadian Satellite Design Challenge's CDR (Critical Design Review).
- Developed understanding of DFM and designing to specification (maximizing resistance to stress while minimizing weight and cost to manufacture).

AIM ENGINEERING CHALLENGE | 1ST PLACE GROUP LEADER

January 2016 - May 2016 | Calgary, AB

- Challenge set by Alta Injection Molding (AIM) to improve the design of a reusable coffee pod for a Keurig machine.
- Developed & tested a new prototype and presented this prototype to the competition host.
- Group placed first; company integrated suggested changes into new pod design.

AUTOMATED FORKLIFT MODEL | GROUP MEMBER

January 2017 - April 2017 | Waterloo, ON

- Developed a model automated forklift for a course project, capable of sorting inventory into different colour coded areas (written in RobotC).
- Received score of 5/5 for robot performance.